Miscellaneous Benjamin Franklin Collections 1710-1822 Mss.B.F85.misc
American Philosophical Society
- Benjamin Franklin Miscellaneous Collection, 1710-1793; Mss.B.F85.[numeral]; 531 items
  - Letter to [Benjamin] Franklin; Cambridge, 1782 Dec. 26; Photostat, 3p.; Mecom, Jane Franklin, 1712-1794
    Concerned about Franklin's health. Desired a copy of his Philosophical and political papers. New of family and friends.
    Printed in Pennsylvania Magazine of History and Biography,v.72, no.3,p.270.
    Van Doren. Franklin-Mecom, pp.217-218.
  - to Mary Stevenson Hewson?, [1782???]; A.L. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - Letter to [Gaetano Filangieri], 1783 January 11; Photostat of L.S. 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    From original in Archive del Museo Civico Gaetano Filangieri, Naples.
    Printed: Smyth, v.9,1
  - Letter to [Richard Oswald], 1783 January 14; Photostat of L. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    From original in possession of Ohio historical society.
    Printed: Smyth, IX, 3-4.
  - [Note on the case of his nephew, Jonathan Williams, respecting the Brig Trio], 1783 January 15; T.c. of D. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    From original in the possession of the Marquees of Lansdowne.
  - to [Mary] Hewson, 1783 January 8; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - Letter to Chev. Rulhiere, [1783?] March 2; A.L. in 3d P. 1p. In French. Seal.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Invitation for a visit that evening.
  - to B. Vaughan, 1783 March 23; Photostat, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Not printed in Smyth.
    Sends newspapers containing articles relating to the barbarities exercised by the British in America; suggests they might be used for propaganda purposes.
  - Letter to M. Lotbiniere, 1783 March 28; L.S. 1p. In French.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Contains a [P.S.] in French in Franklin's hand.
    Replies to letter from M. Lotbiniere of March 26,1783 which is in Franklin Papers - APS.
  - Letter to [Philip] Mazzei, 1783 March; Transcript of L. in 3d P. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Invitation to dinner.
    Transcript made by D. H. Wallace, March 1952.
  - Letter to [Alice De Lancey] Izard, 1783 April 21; L. in 3d P. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Probably written by W.T. Franklin.
    Sends passport desired by Mrs. Izard.
    ---- Bloch film, fr. 10
    (see F.P. 74,3 for Mrs. Izard's letter)
  - Letter to Benj[amin] F[ranklin] Bache, 1783 May 2; Enlargement print of ALS, 2p; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Personal letter to grandson.
    Print made from original in possession of Mrs. Edward W. Smith, April 1943.
  - Letter to Dr. Ingenhauss, 1783 June 1; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Introduces Mr. S. Vaughen who travels with a view of improving himself in mineralogy.
  - to Mrs [Margaret] Stevenson, 1783 July 12; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    (This Letter is apparently dated wrong as Mrs. Stevenson died in January 1783; Franklin knew of this as he wrote to Mary Stevenson Hewson on January 27, 1783 and spoke of her mother's death)
  - Letter to W[illia]m Strahan, 1783 July 29; Enlargement of ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Information about Miss Beckwith.
    From original in possession of Mrs. Arthur Loeb, April 1955.
  - Certification in re Col. Du Bouchet, 1783 August 6; D.S. Portion of 3p. doc.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    In French. Certifies as to the correct transcription of copies of various document by Horatio Gates, George Washington, and others.
    See letter from Bouchet to W.T. Franklin, 1783- ( Franklin Papers, v.108, 85)
  - Letter to Josish Quincey (sis), 1783 Sept. 11; ALS, 4p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    "there never was a good war, or bad Peace."
    Printed: Smyth, 9,93; Quincy, Memoir of J. Quincy, Jr., 1874, 423.
  - Letter to [Mme de Meinieres], 1783 Sept. 12; ALS, 1p. 9x7-1/4.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Will Visit her on Sunday if able. Refers to Mme. Helvetius.
  - Letter to [Johannes Ingenhousz], 1783 Sept. 2; TL Cy, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Concerning the peace treaty. Forwards letter of Banks on balloons.
    Presented by W.J.Bell,Jr., July 1962.
    From original owned by Mrs.J.A. de Rothschild.
  - Letter to Benjamin Vaughan, 1783 October 8; Enlargement print of ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Has on hand 4 copies of volume on electricity, but none of Vaughan's collection [Political...pieces], of which he desires additional copies. Inquires about family.
    From original in possession of Mrs. Frances Vaughan Finletter, March 1951.
  - Letter to Count de Vergennes, 1783 December 14; LS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Introduces Mr. Nesbitt, an American merchant settled at L'Orient.
  - to [Mary. Hewson], 1784 January 1; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    (Printed: Sparks, p.195; Stifler, p.187)
  - Invitation to [Daniel L.] Coit to dinner, 1784 January 14; Photocopy, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - Letter to H[enry] Laurens, 1784 February 15; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Mr. Grand will honor his bills. Regrets that their "employers...have forgotten...to contrive means of decent return for their ministers."
  - Letter to [William] Withering, 1784 March 1; ALS, 1p; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Dr. Withering's letter on calculous complaints and the remedies.
  - Letter to [Mary Stevenson] Hewson, 1784 March 19; A.L. 1p.and end. Mutilated-signature has been cut off. 9x7-1/4.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, IX, 181.
  - Letter to Henry Laurens, 1784 March 31; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Announces arrival of ratification of definitive treaty; has notified Mr.Hartley.
  - Letter to M. LeVeux, Calais, 1784 March 8; L.S. 2p., end. In French. 9x7-1/4.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Thanks him for what he has done for Jay and American prisoners. Explains that consuls will be U.S. citizens. when they are appointed for France.
  - Letter to Dr. Ingenhauss [sic], 1784 April 23; Repro. of ALS. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Sends seeds to Ingenhousz.
    From Hudson Rogue autograph catalog#13, 1986 [?], p. 10.
  - to [Mary] Hewson, 1784 April 29; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    (On the inside of this letter is a letter from Mary Hewson to Mr. Viny)
  - Letter to Felix Frecon (?), 1784 July 3; Photostat of L.S. 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Replies to queries in his letter of June 29 (in APS collection) relative to American regulations of exchange - money merchandise, weights and measures.
    Presented by W.J. Bell, from photostat in Library of Congress.
  - Letter to [Benjamin Franklin]; Vienne, 1784 July 17; Photocopy, 1p.and end. In French. 8x7-1/2.; Born, Ignaz, Edler von, 1742-1791
    Presents his Joannis Physiophili Opuscula.
    Presented by Ellen Gantrell.
    From original in College of Physicians of Philadelphia.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, 1784 July 22, Aug. 6; ALS, 3p.; Franklin, Williem, 1731-1813
    Letter of reconciliation. Mentions W.T. Franklin.
  - Letter to [Mary] Hewson, 1784 August 13; Photocopy, 1p.and end. 11x7-1/2.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    From original in possession of Miss Katherine M. Bradford, Phila. (1969).
    Printed: Smyth, IX, 251-2.
  - Letter to [Richard] Price, 1784 August 2; ALS, 1p. S.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    pertains to Dr. Price's pamphlet of advice to the Americans [Observations on the importance of the American revolution...] and the Turgot letter which it contains. Positive print.
  - Letter to Lord Shelburne, 1784 August 25; T.c. of L. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Introduces the bearer, his grandson William Temple Franklin. Sends pamphlet on animal magnetism.
  - Letter to [Richard] Price, 1784 Sept. 7; ALS, 1p. 9-1/4x7-1/4.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Introduces Count Mirabeau and recommends him.
    For similar letter, see B.Franklin to B.Vaughan; Sept.7,1784, Smyth, 9, 269-270.
  - Letter to Mr. Anisson, 1784 November 10; Enlargement of reproduction 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    New manner of printing. Press for Anisson, bought by William Franklin in London, will be sent to Rouen.
    From reproduction in Le manuscrit autographe, An 8, no.41, 1993, p.21
  - Letter to Messrs. Witel [and Pauche], 1784 November 15; L.S. 2p., end. In French. "No.7"; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, 9, 279. APS has A. Dr. and press copy of this letter; cf. Franklin Papers, 45, 192 and 55, 84.
  - Certification in re Capt. Lewis Joseph de Beaulieu, late of Gen. Count Pulaski's corps, 1784 December 17; Photostat of D.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    From original in Biblioteca Nazionale Centrale of Florence.
  - Letter to the Abbé [Morellet], ca.1784; LS Cy, 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    In French. Typed translation.
    Printed: Smyth, v.7,436, under date of 1779, slightly different wording.
    Printed also in the memoirs of the Abbé Morellet, Paris, 1821.
    See BfF85.1 for another copy of the translation with different illustrations.
  - [Letter to the Abbé Morellet], [1784?]; 3 typed leaves and plate; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Copy of a translation of a letter written by Benjamin Franklin and printed in the Memoirs of the Abbé Morellet, Pari 1821.
  - Letter to M. de Mayer, 1785 January 3; Typescript 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Acknowledges piece entitled Asgill. Sends copy of Book of Constitutions.
    Presented by Antonio Pace; June 1951, from original in Bibliotaca Civica of Turin.
  - Letter to Richard Price, 1785 March 18; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, 9,300.
  - to B. Vaughan., 1785 March 5; Photostat of ALS, 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    This letter is in reply to one written to Franklin by Benjamin Vaughan, Feb. 23, 1785, which the A.P.S owns. Mentions fabricated accounts in British papers which are intended to give unfavorable ideas of America.
  - to B. Vaughan., 1785 April 21; Photostat of L.S with initials. 3p.; Franklin, William Temple
    Pertains to recommendations desired by Mr. and Mrs. Vaughan for Mr. Manning.
  - Letter to [Benjamin] Franklin, 1785 April 26; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Adams, John, 1735-1826
    Asks that Mr. Jefferson inquire for mail for American ministers.
    Framed with engravings and medals of B. Franklin and J. Adams.
  - Letter to B. Franklin, 1785 June 24; LS Cy, 2p.; Roberts, Hugh, ca. 1706-1786
    Comments on old age, and the fact that Philip Syng is the only other living member of the old Junto.
    "Copy of a letter from Hugh Roberts to Benjamin Franklin, - taken from the original now in the possession of the Roberts family, and placed in the hands of R.M. Patterson by Richard Vaux, esq., June 22, 1843."
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, 1785 June 27; Photo. of ALS, 2p.; Jonathan, William, 1750-1815
    Negotitations about a ship calling at Havre fro Dr. Franklin unsuccessful.
    Presented by C.F. Jenkins, 1948.
  - Letter to Ferd[inan]d Grand, 1785 July 16; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Preparations for voyage to America for himself and party, including Mr. Houdon. Transcribes copy of agreement with Messrs. Wallace, Johnson and Muir in repayment of passage, July 8, 1785.
  - to unidentified recipient, 1785 July 22; Photostat, 2p.; Crawford, Adair, 1748-1795
    Pertains to Dr. Franklin's case of the "stone".
  - Letter to [Ferdinand] Grand, 1785 July 24; Photostat, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Is better than he had thought, due to traveling. Concerning his luggage. Friendly letter.
    (from reproduction in J.A. Stargardt Autographen...siche No.12,p.7.)
  - 1785 July 26, Photostat, 1p.; Franklin, William Temple
    Note regarding 48,000 livres borrowed from Benjamin Franklin with which to buy his father's [William Franklin] lands in New Jersey and New York.
    Contains an autograph note signed by B. Franklin, to Mr. Vaughan.
  - Letter to Nathaniel Falconer, 1785 July 28; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    With this is a news clipping (n.d.) transcribing the letter and stating that it was then in the possession of G.W. Childs.
    Printed: Smyth,9,77.
  - "Opinions of some of the Faculty on the case of Dr. Franklin: viz. Drs. Heberden Watson, J. Hunter, Crawford and Mr. J. Hunter.", 1785 July; Photostat of document. 4p.
    Pertains to Franklin's trouble with the "stone."
  - Letter to [Jane] Mecom, 1785 Sept. 19; Repro., 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Safe arrival in America.
  - Letter to William Greene and Catherine Ray Greene, 1785 Sept. 20; Photostat, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    From original in Library of Congress.
    Printed: Smyth,v.9,463.
  - Letter to J[ohn] and [Sarah Van Brugh Livingston] Jay, 1785 Sept. 21; ALS, 2p.and end. 12-1/2x8.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, vol.9, 466-467.
  - Letter to Charles Thomson, 1785 Sept. 26; Enlargement print of ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Acknowledges congratulations on his return home.
  - Address to the American Philosophical Society, 1785 Sept. 27; A.D. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    In Sam. Magaw's hand. Dr. Franklin's answr to ye Address of the Amer. Ph. Socy. soon after he arrived from France.
    Presented by Mrs. Edward W. Smith.
  - Order to T. Jefferson to pay B. Franklin 3600 livres tournois, 1785 Oct. 4; D.S. 1p.; Houdon, Jean Antoine 1741-1828
    Receipted by B. Franklin, Oct. 25, 1785.
  - Letter to [Benjamin] Franklin, 1785 Oct. 4; ADrS, 2p.; Jay, John, 1745- 1829
    Printed: Sparks, 10, 228: Bigelow, 9, 268. For letter sent see Franklin Papers, 33,204
  - Letter to Patrick Henry, 1785 October 8; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printing type sold to the state of Virginia.
    Photostat presented by Thomas F O'Donnel, March 1953.
    from original which was then in the possession of the Thomas R. Proctor collection of the Munson-Williams-Proctor Institute, Utica, N.Y.
    Printed: W.W. Henry, Patrick Henry, 1891, III,323.
  - Letter to M. de Chaumont, 1785 October 20; A.L. 2p. (incomplete); Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, v.9, 469.
  - Letter to William Ellery, 1785 November 14; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Acknowledges letter of October 10 [in APS collection] enclosing one from Mr. Vernon.
  - Deed for portion of land on which the old goal and workhouse stood, Third and High streets, issued to John Hubley, 1785 November 23; DS, 1p.; Pennsylvania. Supreme Executive Council
    Seal Parchment Recorded on April 27, 1786.
  - Letter to [Benjamin Franklin], 1785 Nov. 27; L.S. 1p.; Smallwood, William, 1732-1792
    Printed: Penna. Archives,ser.I,vol.10, 542.
  - Letter to unidentified recipient, [1785?] December 14 Wednesday morng.; ALS, lp.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Will search for letters as soon as he returns from the state house.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin; dated Philadelphia, 1786 Jan. 12; A.Dr. of L. 6p. F.; Ruston, Thomas, ca. 1739-1804
    Re: smoky chimneys.
    Purchased from the American Autograph Shop, April 1939, $25 and a set of the Franklin calendar.
    Printed (slight difference in wording in first paragraph) in American Philosophical Society, Transactions, v.2, 231.
  - Letter to Jonathan Williams, jr., Boston, 1786 January 19; ALS, 2p., end.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, 9,480.
  - Letter to John Hyacinth de Magellan, 1786 January 24; L.S. 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    The APS and the Magellanic premium.
    Printed almost entirely: Early Minutes, Jan. 20, 1786.
  - Letter to Jonathan Williams, jr., Boston, 1786 February 16; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, 9,487.
  - Warrant to John Lukens to have surveyed plot of ground in Westmoreland Co. for John Davis, 1786 April 27; PrDS, 1p.; Pennsylvania. Supreme Executive Council
  - Order to David Rittenhouse to pay the estate of William Wilson £5.16.10, 1786 May 8; PrDS, 1p.; Pennsylvania. Supreme Executive Council
  - Patent issued to John Cornman, for a tract of land in Westmoreland, 1786 May 9; 1p.; Pennsylvania. Supreme Executive Council
    Presented by Mr. Samuel H. McVitty, March 1955. A similar patent for another piece of ground exists for this day to the same person.
    Printed D. filled in, S: B. Franklin, Presid.
  - Order to David Rittenhouse to pay Francis Allison [sic], 1786 May 9; Photostat, 1p.; Pennsylvania. Supreme Executive Council
  - Letter to J. Sargent, 1786 May 25; ALS, 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Suggestions concerning collection of depts due Mr. Sergent from Americans. Is under obligations to Mr. Sergent for many kindnesses.
  - to Sarah Bache, 1786 May 29; Mecom, Jane
  - Letter to M. [Jean Baptisse] LeRoy, 1786 August 15; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, v.9,335; see also G. Chinard, Strange fortune of the volumes of the "Transactions," in A.P.S. Library Bulletin for 1944, p.26.
  - Letter to John Jay, 1786 August 24; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth 9, 537.
  - Order to David Rittenhouse to pay David Evans, 1786 Sept. 19; D.S.: B. Franklin. 1p. John Nicholson and D. Evans. 9-1/2x8.; Pennsylvania. Supreme Executive Council
    Forgery
    Presented by J. Bennett Nolan.
  - Certification in re character of Josiah Flagg, 1786 Sept. 4; Photostat of A.D.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    ---- photostat of typed c. in New England Historic Genealogical Society.
    From original in possession of the Harvard school of business administration.
  - Order to David Rittenhouse to pay James Worthing; In Council, Philadelphia, 1786 Sept. 7; Photostat. 1p. Forgery.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - Letter to M. de Chaumont, 1786 October 7; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, v.9, 542.
  - Letter to the Secretary of Council, 1786 November 21; ALS, 1p. 3x7.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Requisition for commission for Edward Shippen and others.
  - Letter to the President...Supreme executive council [Benjamin Franklin]; Wardens office, 1786 Dec. 13; L.S: Nath Falconer, John Hazelwood, Joe: Bullock. 1p., end. in B.F.'s hand.; Falconer, Nathaniel
    Send certain information [ in re Spanish man of war]
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, Pennsylvania, 1786 Dec. 19; ALS, Cp., end. In French with translatin in red ink, in hand of B.Franklin, 12-1/2x7-3/4.; Otto, Lewis William
    Concerning the extradition of a French witiser. De Bressines.
  - An account of the highest court of Judicature in Pennsylvania, viz. The court of the press, [1786?]; Copy of D. 7p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: American museum, v.6, pp.295-297.1786.
  - Letter to [Benjamin] Franklin; Grosvenor Square, 1787 Jan. 27; ALS, 2p.; Adams, John, 1735-1826
    Sends copies of his work [Defence of the Constitution] for Dr. Franklin and the Philosophical Society. Dilly's desires to publish a new edition of Franklin's works with the addition of a sketch of his life.
    See 342.73:Adld volume presented.
  - Patent issued to Baltzer Knertzer for a tract of land called "Fortune" in Newberry township, York county, 1787 January 30; Photostat of D.S: B. Franklin (president) 1p. Seal.; Pennsylvania. Supreme Executive Council
    Presented by Dr. John Witthoft, from original owned by Mr. Fredericks, Harrisburg, Pa June 1954.
  - Letter to Gen. [Arthur] St. Clair, 1787 February 13; Photostat of L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    introduces the bearer, M. de Chaumont. Presented by M.Dumont.
  - Petition to Benjamin Franklin, president of the Supreme Executive Council of Pennsylvania, for a bankruptey commission against Charles Young, sworn before B. Franklin, 1787 Mar. 2; D.S. 2p.; Bond, Thomas
    Contains also appointment of commission signed by B. Franklin. F.
    Purchased from F.G. Sweet, September 1939, $37.50.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin [President of Pennsylvania], 1787 Mar.; ALS, 3p.; Balliet, Stephen
    Observations on the Lehigh river; the advantages which would result to the city of Phila., the counties of Northumberland... from the navigation thereof... roads to the Suequehanah.
    Printed: Pa, archives, v.11, 131.
  - Order to David Rittenhouse to pay John Baird 45£ for his attendance in Council...and mileage; In Council, Philadelphia, 1787 April 12; DS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Receipted by Jno. Baird.
  - Deed to Daniel Hartung for a tract of land called "Daniels fancy" in Northumberland County, 1787 April 12; DS, 1p.; Pennsylvania. Supreme Executive Council
    Presented by Morris Duane; December 28, 1962.
  - Account with Benjamin Franklin, 1787 May 14-July 5.; D. 2p.; Sybert, Sebastian
    Contains receipt written in Franklin's hand; July 7, 1787. Photostat obtained when the document was in the possession of Mr. Loeb, 1953.
  - Letter to [Sir William] Herschel, 1787 May 18; Photo.of ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    (from original in Biblioteca Estense of Modena, Codici e Mss Campori ,Busta 209)
    Printed: Smyth, vol.IX, 584.
    Presented by Antonio Pace; May 1961.
  - Patent issued to Samuel Titmus for a tract of land called "the Folly" in Northumberland county, 1787 May 21; Photostat of D.S: B. Franklin (president) 1p. Seal.; Pennsylvania. Supreme Executive Council
    Accompanying this document is an enlargement of a survey of the tract, made by John Lukens, Feb.26,1787.
    From the original owned by T. Kenneth Wood, Williamsport, Pa.
  - Order to David Rittenhouse to pay Edward Burd for travelling expenses as judge of the Supreme court, 1787 June 13; DS, 1p.; Pennsylvania. Supreme Executive Council
  - Patent issued to John McKee for tract of land called "Allegany Tract" in Westmoreland co, 1787 June 16; DS, 1p.; Pennsylvania. Supreme Executive Council
    Inrolled in Patent book...June 18, 1787.
  - Deed for lot No. 1983 at 8th and Chestnut streets, to John Steinmetz, 1787 June 28; PrDS, 1p.; Pennsylvania. Supreme Executive Council
    "Disposing of...lots...late of the estate of Joseph Galloway...forfeited to this Commonwealth."
    "Inrolled in the Rolls office... August 4, 1787."
  - Account with Christian Sybard [Seybert], 1787 June 30-July 18; D.S. (in German): Christian Seybert. 1p. 8-1/2x6-1/2. (see Franklin Papers.); Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    For hauling dirt.
  - Letter to D[avid] Hartley, [1787? ca.] June; Typed c. of L. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    From original in possession of Stanley Neyhart.
  - Petition by Ann Bell with notation by Franklin, 1787 August 20; D.S. 2p. 8x13.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Concerns bankruptcy commission of Clarkson, Hughes, Baynton, and Bacher in case of Joseph Page; Petition for same by Ann Bell; directed so by Franklin in appended note.
    (See. Franklin papers.)
  - Order to David Rittenhouse to pay Samuel Hill £20.5 for services rendered, 1787 Sept. 2; DS, 1p.; Supreme executive council, Pennsylvania
    Presented by Mrs. Arthur Bloch as a forgery from her husband's estate, July 1954.
  - Order to David Rittenhouse to pay Samuel Hill £20.5sh for services in Council, 1787 Sept. 2; DS Cy, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Presented by Mr. S.H. McVitty, March 1955.
  - Order to David Rittenhouse to pay Silas Curtis; In Council, Philadelphia, 1787 Sept. 20; Photostat of D.S. 1p.,end. by D.Rittenhouse.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - Grant of land in Westmoreland County to John Beatman Webster.., 1787 Sept. 29; With this was a picture of B. Franklin by St. Aubin after Cochin.; Pennsylvania. Supreme Executive Council
  - Letter to [Gastano] Filangieri;phila, 1787 October 14; Photostat, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    From Original in Archivo del Musec Civico Gaetano Filangieri, Naples.
    Printed: Smyth, v.9,618
  - Petition to Benjamin Franklin, president, Supreme Executive Council, 1787 Oct. 18; ALS, 2p. Contains A.N.S. by B. Franklin to the Secretary of Council.; Lea, Thomas